(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-22T09:51:15.402957",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
け放した窓に 廻る乱舞の DEEP SKY AH 仰いで...
Opening the window to the swirling deep sky, ah, looking up...
AH 叫んで... 飛び出す GO
Ah, shouting out... rushing out, GO!
履き潰した ROCKING SHOES
Wearing out my rocking shoes,
踏み上げる PUDDLE
splashing through the puddles.
君は CLEVER AH, REMEMBER
You are clever, ah, remember—
あの虹を渡って あの朝に帰りたい
Crossing that rainbow, I want to return to that morning.
あの夢を並べて 二人歩いた GLAMOROUS DAYS
Lining up those dreams, the glamorous days we walked together.
明け透けな愛に 何の価値もないの?
"Does transparent love have no value at all?"
AH 嘆いて... 吐き出す GO
Ah, lamenting... breathing out, GO!
飲み干して ROCK'N'ROLL
Drinking it all down with rock 'n' roll,
息上がる BATTLE
breathless in battle.
君の FLAVOR AH, REMEMBER
Your flavor, ah, remember—
あの星を集めて この胸に飾りたい
Gathering those stars, I want to decorate this chest.
あの夢をつないで 二人踊った GLAMOROUS DAYS
Connecting those dreams, the glamorous days we danced together.
眠れないよ! SUNDAY MONDAY
I can't sleep! Sunday, Monday,
稲妻 TUESDAY WEDNESDAY THURSDAY
Lightning Tuesday, Wednesday, Thursday,
雪花... FRIDAY SATURDAY
Snowflakes... Friday, Saturday,
七色 EVERYDAY
Rainbow-colored everyday.
闇雲 消える FULL MOON
Dark clouds fade, full moon—
応えて 僕の声に
Respond to my voice—
あの雲を払って 君の未来照らしたい
Clearing away those clouds, I want to illuminate your future.
この夢を抱いて 一人歩くよ GLORIOUS DAYS
Embracing this dream, I'll walk alone, glorious days.
あの虹を渡って あの朝に帰りたい
Crossing that rainbow, I want to return to that morning.
あの夢を並べて 二人歩いた GLAMOROUS DAYS
Lining up those dreams, the glamorous days we walked together.
GLAMOROUS SKY
開け放した窓に 廻る乱舞の DEEP SKY
The deep sky cavorts in circles outside my open window
AH 仰いで...
Ah... I look up...
「繰り返す日々は何の意味があるの?」
“What meaning is there in these repetitive days?”
AH 叫んで...
Ah... I shout...
飛び出す GO 履き潰した ROCKING SHOES
And take off, go, my broken-in rocking shoes
跳ね上げる PUDDLE フラッシュバック 君は CLEVER
Splash through puddles, flashback – you were clever
AH, REMEMBER
あの虹を渡って あの朝に帰りたい
I want to cross that rainbow and go back to that morning
あの夢を並べて 二人歩いた GLAMOROUS DAYS
To those glamorous days when our dreams aligned and we walked together
「明け渡した愛に 何の価値もないの?」
“Isn’t there any value in surrendered love?”
AH 嘆いて...
Ah... I lament...
吐き出す GO 飲み干して ROCK'N'ROLL
And spit it out, go, drink down all the rock n’ roll
息上がる BATTLE フラッシュバック 君の FLAVOR
And revive for the battle, flashback – your flavor
AH, REMEMBER
あの星を集めて この胸に飾りたい
I want to collect those stars and decorate my heart
あの夢をつないで 二人踊った GLAMOROUS DAYS
In those glamorous days our dreams connected and we danced together
GLAMOROUS DAYS
眠れないよ! SUNDAY MONDAY
I can’t sleep! Sunday, Monday
稲妻 TUESDAY WEDNESDAY THURSDAY
Lightning Tuesday, Wednesday, Thursday
雪花... FRIDAY SATURDAY
Snowflakes... Friday, Saturday
七色 EVERYDAY 闇云 消える FULL MOON
Rainbow-colored everyday, the full moon disappears into dark clouds
応えて 僕の声に あの雲を払って
Answer my voice, I want to blow away the clouds
君の未来照らしたい この夢を抱えて
And light up your future, in these glorious days I carry my dream
一人歩くよ GLORIOUS DAYS
And walk alone... glorious days
あの虹を渡って あの朝に帰りたい
I want to cross that rainbow and go back to that morning
あの夢を並べて 二人歩いた GLAMOROUS DAYS
To those glamorous days when our dreams aligned and we walked together
GLAMOROUS SKY...
裏路地の真ん中で 慣れない景色と好かない匂いに
In the middle of the back alley, surrounded by unfamiliar scenery and scents I dislike,
私は覆われて 染まっていくんでしょ
I'm being covered and getting stained by them.
私は怖がりで
I am a coward,
知らないことには手を付けず
never touching things I don't know,
誰かがやって来て 毒味をするまで待っていた
waiting until someone comes and tastes it for safety.
することは単純で マニュアル通りの生活を 来る日も淡々と過ごしていた
What I do is simple, living life according to the manual, spending every day monotonously.
そういやさ そういやさ
Come to think of it, come to think of it,
昨日の私もこうだった
yesterday was just the same for me.
そういやさ そういやさ
Come to think of it, come to think of it.
弱い音を吐いている
Uttering weak complaints,
薄っぺらい人間です
I am a shallow person.
一歩前に出るのはやめときます
I'll refrain from stepping forward
絡まれたくないからさ
because I don't want to get tangled up in trouble.
描いた理想像に現実味がないから
Since the ideal image I drew lacks reality,
近づけないよう生きときます
I'll live so as not to get too close.
明日も同じよう過ごしときます
I'll spend tomorrow the same way.
裏路地の真ん中で いつもの夕日を薄目で眺めて
In the middle of the back alley, gazing lazily at the usual sunset,
胸内で呟いた 「いつまで続くんだろう」
murmuring in my heart, "How long will this last?"
そういやさ そういやさ
Come to think of it, come to think of it,
昨日の夕飯これだった
yesterday's dinner was this same meal too.
そういやさ そういやさ
Come to think of it, come to think of it.
臆病で切りが悪い
Cowardly and irresolute,
意気地無し人間です
I am a spineless person.
一歩後ろに下がって逃げときます
I'll take a step back and run away.
目立ちたくなんからないからさ
Because I don't want to stand out at all.
描いた理想像に現実味がないから
Since the ideal image I drew lacks reality,
近づけないよう生きときます
I'll live so as not to get too close.
明日も同じよう過ごしときます
I'll spend tomorrow the same way.
弱い音を吐いている
Uttering weak complaints,
薄っぺらい人間です
I am a shallow person.
一歩前に出るのはやめときます
I'll refrain from stepping forward
絡まれたくないからさ
because I don't want to get tangled up in trouble.
ため息ばっかりで 吸う息足りないの
With nothing but sighs, running out of breath,
きっとそう上手くはいかないけどさ
surely things won't go so smoothly, but
試しにちゃんと生きてみよう
let's try living properly just for once.
決まった言葉垂れてまたヒューマン
Common phrases spill out, another human,
ちょっとステキな晒し者ね
What a charming spectacle you are.
果てた命眺めて全てを無視した
Gazing at expired lives, ignoring it all,
額縁の中で1000年生きてるのさ
Living for a thousand years inside a frame.
知らない偉い人が
Some wise man I don't know
石に文字彫って祈って
Carved letters into stone and prayed,
気の狂った誰かが
Someone out of their mind
ホワイトを塗りたくった
Coated it all in white.
ガラクタの上で
On top of the junk,
くどいプロポーズを待って
Waiting for a tedious proposal,
あつい口づけを交わすとき鳴り響くクラクション
Horns echoing when passionate kisses are exchanged.
狂ったフリでごまかしていこうぜ
Let's fake being crazy and brush it off.
骨も残らぬパパママよ
Oh mom and dad, leaving not even bones behind,
ラッタッタ口ずさんだアダムの星
Humming "rattatta", Adam's star.
祭り上げては落としたヒューマン
A human worshipped and then cast down,
ちょっと皮肉なオークションね
What a slightly ironic auction.
初めの初めに構えが全てを無視した
Right from the start, her posture ignored everything,
あなたの気持ちが1000年生きるのさ
Your feelings will live on for a thousand years.
左利きの直した方も消えない傷のえぐり方も
How to fix being left-handed, how to carve non-fading scars,
拒って感情の消し方も忘れたらしい
It seems I even forgot how to reject and erase emotions.
進化か退化か分からないが顔も見られず殺せるらしい
Evolution or devolution? It seems you can kill without seeing faces.
荒屋の生活は思い出すだけ無駄らしい
Life in the dilapidated hut—remembering it is just a waste.
狂ったフリでごまかしていこうぜ
Let's fake being crazy and brush it off.
ちょっと笑える話をしよう
Let's talk about something a bit funny.
あはは泣き腫らしたあの人とはお別れね
Ahaha, time to say goodbye to that person who cried their eyes out.
曲がって歩いて転がったヒューマン
Walking crookedly and tumbling down, a human,
ちょっと皮肉なアディショナルタイム
A somewhat ironic additional time.
あなたの気持ちに賭けてみたいのさ
I want to take a bet on your feelings.
一生このまま尻尾の可愛い一枚で繋がれた奴隷か？
A slave bound for life by just a cute tail?
喉元に噛み付く牙はまだあるかい？
Do you still have fangs to bite at the throat?
残り時間の少ないヒューマン見ててあげる楽しませて
Humans with little time left, let me watch, entertain me.
生き汚く生きて何かを作ったらあなたの気持ちが1000年生きられるかもしれないから
Living stubbornly, if you create something, your feelings might live on for a thousand years.
皆さん、はは、ありがとうございます！聞いてくれて…
Everyone, haha, thank you so much for listening...
そして、1周年記念ライブに来てくれて、ありがとうございます！
And thank you so much for coming to the 1st anniversary live!
1曲目は「グラマラススカイ」で、これは生で歌ったので緊張で声がプルプルでしたね。
The first song was "GLAMOROUS SKY", and since I sang it live, my voice was shaking so much from nerves.
信じられないぐらい震えてました。びっくりしました。リハと全然違いました！
I was shaking unbelievably. I was so shocked. It was totally different from rehearsal!
「ヨワネハキ」続いて「1000年生きてる」
"Yowane Haki", followed by "1000-nen Ikiteru"
よろしくおねがいします。
Nice to meet you, and thank you so much! I look forward to it.
そして、えー、次の曲なのですが、さかがたがずっと懸念していた
And the next song is one Sakamata has been worrying about a lot...
それでは聞いてください。「ストリーミングハート」
So please listen to "Streaming Heart"!
あれやこれや言いますが
Though the things I say might not make sense
どうか探し続けてみせて
Please, go and find me
ウソと本音の間
In the space between truth and lies
うまく隠しといたんだ
I am hidden away
二人じゃダメなんだどうして
For the two of us, so useless alone...
二人になればハッピー
Together, we were oh-so happy
そのうち一人が嫌で
Until one of us became discontent
一人がいいとか言って
And said we were better lonely
固定しようもない感情の行き着く先はどこでしょう
Where do these feelings lead?
溺れそうになった代償にまた酸素を見つけちゃんだ
I attempted to gasp for air once more
弱虫だね
A coward through and through...
堕ちることが心地よくてさ
How sweet it is to fall!
アイマイにしたいのさ
I wanna get rid of this love
好きでいてだって歪んでく内声
And if I could make you despise me, that would be so great!
二人じゃダメなんだどうして
For the two of us, so useless alone...
二人になればハッピー
Together, we were oh-so happy
そのうち一人が嫌で
Until one of us became discontent
一人がいいとか言って
And said we were better lonely
いっそ僕がもう一人なら
If I could finally be all by myself again
それはそれでハッピーだ
Then I could be happy once again!
今日は僕が女の子 演じ合ってバカみたいにさ
Today I'll put on a show playing the girl
このままだと知りながらも
Even if being by myself is constant suffering
やめられないのさ
I don't wanna step out of line
アイマイにしたいのさ
I wanna get rid of this love
好きでいてだって歪んでく内声
And if I could make you despise me, that would be great!
バイバイにしたいのさ
I wanna make this our goodbye!
あれやこれや言いますが
Though the things I say might not make sense
どうか探し続けてみせて
Please, go and find me
ウソと本音の間
In the space between truth and lies
うまく隠しといたんだ
I am hidden away
あ、急いで、急がなきゃ。
Hurry, I've got to hurry!
ほっ…
Hot...
とっ…あ、え、え、できた！できて、できた！
To... Oh, I- I made it!
できた！できてた！
I made it! I made it!
ちょ、待って。かっこいいじゃん、これ。
Wait, that's pretty stylish!
あ、あー。
Ah, wow!
あ、なんだここ。うわ、すごい！
What's this? Wow, amazing!
焼き肉屋さんある！
There's a yakiniku restaurant!
え、この後食べに行くか。
Should I go eat there afterwards?
食べに来た。え、え、待って、なんか
I came to eat. Eh?
レンタルルーム？なんですかこれ。
Rental room? What is this?
これ、見ていいやつですか？
Is this place worth checking out?
へー、お、かん…あ、へー。ほー、そんなのもあるんですねー。
Oh, really? They have places like that too?
え、なんか、あ、あれ見て！
Wait, look at that!
なんか、え？あ、すごい！かわいい女の子！なんだろ、え、かわいいみちょころ。アンコールしてよね？あ
Look at that giant billboard! It says "Do an encore!"
えー、誰かがライブやってんのかな？誰だろうね。
Wait, someone's doing a live stream? Who could it be?
これ、みんなアンコールしたほうがいいんじゃない？さすがに。なんか熱い感じですね。
Everyone should definitely do an encore! It feels so fitting.
え、これ、これいいよ。
Oh, this is nice!
え、ちょ、ちょっとみんな、どっかのライブもしね、見てるんだったら、アンコールしたほうがいいと思います。
Hey everyone, if you're watching the live stream, I think you should do an encore!
この後面接で会ったりとか、なんとか。もしれないけど。
We can meet up later or something... Well, I don't really know.
ありがとうございました！いぎまーす！
Anyway, thank you! Let's go!
もっかいいいすか？もっかい、もっかい行くよ。
Let's try that again! Let's go again!
笑ってるけどさ、マジ……
You're laughing, but seriously...
さっき大変なんだよね、はっ
it was so rough just now, ha!
はっ！ ああー……ちょっと待って
Ha! Ah... wait a second.
AC感度か……いやー、はあ。
AC sensitivity... man, phew.
じゃ、最後にバジッと決めて
Well, I'll nail it this time
さようならしますね。
and say goodbye.
いきますよ。
Here we go.
はっ！ おっ、いえーい！
Ha! Oh, yeah!
報酬は入社後並行路線で
The reward is a parallel line after joining the company
東京は愛せど何もない
Tokyo is lovable, but there's nothing here.
リッケン620頂戴
Give me a Rickenbacker 620.
19万も持っていない
I don't even have 190,000 yen,
御茶ノ水
Ochanomizu.
マーシャルの匂いで飛んじゃって大変さ
Flying with the smell of Marshall is tough.
毎晩絶頂に達しているだけ
Just reaching climax every night
ラット1つを商売道具にしているさ
Using a single RAT as a business tool
そしたらベンジーが肺に映ってトリップ
And Benji is reflected in my lungs and I trip
最近は銀座で警察ごっこ
Lately, playing cops and robbers in Ginza
国境は越えても盛者必衰
Even if you cross borders, the prosperous must decline
領収書を書いて頂戴
Please write me a receipt
税理士なんて就いていない
No tax accountant is following
後楽園
Korakuen
将来僧になって結婚して欲しい
I want you to become a monk in the future and marry me
毎晩寝具で優遊するだけ
Just playing games in bed every night
ピザ屋の彼女になってみたい
I want to become a pizza parlor's girlfriend
そしたらベンジー、あたしをグレッチで殴って
And then Benji, hit me with a Gretsch
青嚙んで熟して頂戴
Bite the green and ripen, please
終電で帰るってば池袋
I'm going home on the last train, Ikebukuro
領収書を書いて頂戴
Please write me a receipt
税理士なんて就いていない
No tax accountant is following
後楽園
Korakuen
将来僧になって結婚して欲しい
I want you to become a monk in the future and marry me
毎晩寝具で優遊するだけ
Just playing games in bed every night
ピザ屋の彼女になってみたい
I want to become a pizza parlor's girlfriend
そしたらベンジー、あたしをグレッチで殴って
And then Benji, hit me with a Gretsch
青嚙んで熟して頂戴
Bite the green and ripen, please
終電で帰るってば池袋
I'm going home on the last train, Ikebukuro
領収書を書いて頂戴
Please write me a receipt
終電で帰るってば...
I'm going home on the last train...
マーシャルの匂いで飛んじゃって大変さ
Flying with the smell of Marshall is tough.
毎晩絶頂に達しているだけ
Just reaching climax every night
ラット1つを商売道具にしているさ
Using a single RAT as a business tool
そしたらベンジーが肺に映ってトリップ
And Benji is reflected in my lungs and I trip
最近は銀座で警察ごっこ
Lately, playing cops and robbers in Ginza
国境は越えても盛者必衰
Even if you cross borders, the prosperous must decline
領収書を書いて頂戴
Please write me a receipt
税理士なんて就いていない
No tax accountant is following
後楽園
Korakuen
将来僧になって結婚して欲しい
I want you to become a monk in the future and marry me
毎晩寝具で優遊するだけ
Just playing games in bed every night
ピザ屋の彼女になってみたい
I want to become a pizza parlor's girlfriend
そしたらベンジー、あたしをグレッチで殴って
And then Benji, hit me with a Gretsch
青嚙んで熟して頂戴
Bite the green and ripen, please
終電で帰るってば池袋
I'm going home on the last train, Ikebukuro
みんな、ありがとう！
Everyone, thank you!
まだまだライブは続きまーす！
The live stream is still going!
このあと、この後も頑張るので応援よろしくお願いします！
I'll keep doing my best after this, so please support me!
貫いて、この心を
Piercing right through this heart,
思い切り突き刺して
stabbing deep with all my might!
火照ったままで知らぬふりはもうやめて
Stop playing dumb while you're still all flushed.
暇つぶしには飽きたのよ
I'm so sick of just passing time.
纏ったビニールを脱がせたいの
I want to strip off this vinyl wrapping
お前の思惑から無邪気に抜け出して
and innocently slip away from your schemes.
「さよなら、愛を込めて」
"Farewell, infused with love."
気の済むまで暴れなよ
Go wild until you're satisfied.
哀れだろ？
Pitiful, aren't I?
むしろお洒落するぜ
Rather, I'll dress it up nicely.
喧騒に上がる煙に飛び込んでいくだけさ
Just diving right into the rising smoke of the commotion!
「遊びじゃないの、あなたには」なんて適当に言葉暴れさせて
Letting words run wild like, "It's not a game to you," so casually.
喧騒に上がる煙に薪をくべろ
Throw more fuel on the smoke rising in the uproar!
今日も軽やかなステップで誤魔化し誤魔化し生きて行こうじゃないか
Today too, with light-hearted steps, let's just fake our way through life, shall we?
真っ暗な明日に欺かれてさ
Deceived by a pitch-black tomorrow,
誰に向けたナイフなの？何に突き動かされてる？
whose heart is this knife aimed at? What drives you forward?
苦しいだけの現実はもうやめて
Stop with this reality that's only painful.
「さよなら、愛を込めて」
"Farewell, infused with love."
息も吸いなよ、この街の有余る空気を焦げ付いたビニールの中からストリートへ抜け出せたなら
Breathe in deep the excess air of this town—if you can break out of the scorched vinyl into the street,
遊び切るんだこの世界、喧騒、狂乱に雨あられ、掠め取ったもん勝ちでしょ？
you can play this world to the fullest! Uproar, frenzy, a hail of rain—finders keepers, right?
さよなら、愛を込めて、思いの丈を着飾って、どんちゃん騒ぎのナイトクラブから
Farewell, with love poured in, dressing up in all my feelings, from the uproarious nightclub—
さよなら、愛を込めて、思いの丈を着飾って、繋いだその手は離さないで
Farewell, with love poured in, dressing up in all my feelings, don't let go of the hand we linked.
いいね
Sounds good.
息巻くのよ、この港の爆発だろう、盛衰するぜ
Bustle with energy, this port must be exploding, rising and falling!
激動、時のルーツを越えて飛び込んでいくだけさ
Just diving across the roots of turbulent times!
「遊びじゃないのよあなたとは」なんて嘘で固めたこの世なら
If this world is built on lies like "It's not a game to you,"
冗談も怖い今日でしょ？
even jokes are scary today, right?
さよなら、愛を込めて、思いの丈を着飾って、どんちゃん騒ぎのナイトクラブから
Farewell, with love poured in, dressing up in all my feelings, from the uproarious nightclub—
息巻くのよ、この港の爆発だろう、盛衰するぜ
Bustle with energy, this port must be exploding, rising and falling!
激動、時のルーツを越えて飛び込んでいくだけさ
Just diving across the roots of turbulent times!
最後の最後には、ニヤリと笑ってみせる
At the very, very end, I'll flash a grinning smile.
前のときはね結構お披露目っていうのもあって、
Back then, there was sort of a big reveal,
ふざけたりとかね、おーくって
so I messed around a bit,
あの意味のわからないギャンブルが始まったりとかね、して澱ましたが、
and played some gambling games with no real meaning,
今回はですね、坂又クロヱのデビューから1年間ま、成長だったりとか
but this time, since it's been a year since Sakamata Chloe's debut, showing my growth,
ま、坂又の活動の決勝みたいなものかなと思うので、
and kind of the culmination of Sakamata's activities,
今回はあんまりふざけたりとかしないで、まじめに ちょっとみんなにお見せできたらなと思って、
this time I didn't want to mess around too much, and wanted to seriously show everyone—
たくさんダンスとか歌も練習してきたし、
I've practiced dancing and singing a lot,
結構ね、このライブの構成自体も考えたりしましたので、
and I've thought quite a bit about the composition of this live concert too,
みんなもね、あの、真剣に、も、あの、真剣に？真剣に見てもらえたら嬉しいなって思います。
so I hope you'll all watch it earnestly—um, earnestly? Watch it with all your heart, and I'd be so happy.
いや、本当にね、あっという間だったとも思うし、でも坂又は
Man, truly, it feels like it went by in a flash, but for Sakamata,
なんかまだまだこれから先もやりたいことがいっぱいあるから、
I feel like there's still so much more I want to do going forward,
これから先のためにももっともっと前までよりもさらに頑張んなきゃなと思って、今回このライブに向けて頑張ってきているので、
so for the future, I felt I needed to work even harder than before, and I've been working hard towards this live stream,
みんなも楽しみに見てくれてたら嬉しいなと思います。
so I'd be so happy if you all watch it with excitement.
最後まで見てくれると嬉しいな。みんなもいつも本当にありがとね。
I'd be glad if you watch until the very end. Thank you all so much, as always.
後半になったらまたいろいろお告知などもあるかもなので、ぜひぜひ最後まで見てね。最後まで頑張りよ。
There might be various announcements and such in the second half, so please watch till the very end. I'll do my best till the end!
真剣に頑張れます。
I'll work hard with all my heart.
はーい、みんな！どうだったでしょうか！坂又
Hii everyone! How was it?! Sakamata
すごい頑張ったんだけど、
tried really, really hard, but—
どう、どうですか？
How, how was it?
ちょっと運動音痴ながら、あの、たくさんダンスの方やらせていただきまして、なんというか、よしよししてもらえたらなと思うのですが、どうでしょうそのへん。
Though I'm a bit clumsy at sports, I did so much dancing, so I'd love it if you could pat my head and praise me. What do you think about that?
みんなありがとね。
Thank you all so much.
いや、あのね、ストリーミングハートがねマジで！マジで息が続かないんだよね。本当に。
Man, you know, Streaming Heart is seriously—seriously, I couldn't catch my breath at all! Really.
めちゃくちゃ好きな曲だし、今回のライブに合うなと思って頑張らせていただいたんですが、
It's a song I love so much, and I thought it fit this live, so I gave it my best, but—
やっぱねダンスしながらとかきつかったし、坂又ね、この、この動きがマジで苦手すぎて、
As expected, dancing while singing was tough, and Sakamata, man, I'm just so bad at this, this movement—
大変でした。
it was so hard.
そして前のさ、ね、スティックもね、あの、全部フルでね、あの、踊るっていうね、ちょっと、あの、何を何を頑張ったんだって感じなんですけど、そこは。
And the stick dance before too, dancing the whole thing in full—it's like, what on earth did I work so hard for there?
すごい頑張らしていただきましたそこを。
I worked really hard on that part.
なのでね、もうバテバテだったんですが、そのあとビニールね！行けましたね！
So I was totally exhausted, but after that, Vinyl! We made it!
ビニールが一番なんかうまくいった気がする。どうでしょう？ね、楽しんでくれた？
I feel like Vinyl went the best out of all of them. How was it? Did you enjoy it?
ね、楽しんでくれたらいいな、みんな。
Right, I hope you all enjoyed it.
で、みんなの応援のコメント見ながらだったからね、ちょっとずつ緊張がほぐれてきました。
And because I was reading everyone's cheering comments, my nervousness started to melt away little by little.
では、ここになんですけど、
Now, here's the thing—
水族館にあるものを用意して、もらいました！なんだと思う？
we had something prepared that you'd find in an aquarium! What do you think it is?
こちらです！
Here it is!
真剣にやりますから坂又は、よろしくお願いしますね。
Sakamata is going to do this seriously, so please treat me well.
真剣ですよ、皆さん。真剣に見てください。
I'm serious, everyone. Please watch seriously.
すげえ！よく撮ったよね、これ。
Amazing! You filmed this well, didn't you?
じゃあどう、ちょっとやってみるか。坂又ね、実力ね、詳しい内容教えてもらってないんだよね、これ。教えてくれなかったの、ギア？
Well then, shall we try it out? Sakamata, you know, I haven't been told the detailed contents, right? They didn't tell me, Gear?
ずるん！
Spin!
はい！
Right!
あー、だめだわ。
Ah, that's no good.
あ、もう一回！ずるん！
Ah, once more! Spin!
いやでも通常ステージですね。通常ステージもいいけどね。
Well, but it's the regular stage. The regular stage is nice too, though.
行くよ、ボーダー。はい！
Here we go, border. Ready!
楽しんで！あ、えっ！え？
Have fun! Oh, what?! What?
沙花叉クロヱ
Sakamata Chloe
え、追加あるか？あるか？
Eh, is there an extra? Is there?
はっ！
Ha!
ないか。まあ、さすがにね、
Guess not. Well, of course,
そんな簡単に当たんないよな。
it wouldn't hit that easily.
はい！あ、熱そう！熱そう！
Here! Ah, looks hot! Looks hot!
はい！
Here!
いや、来い、来い、来い！なんだこの仮面？何なんだろう、これ。はい！
Come on, come, come! What's with this mask? What on earth is this? Here!
あ、リプレイ？はい！
Ah, a replay? Here!
ああ、どうなんでしょうね。こっからうまいくんでしょうか。
Ah, I wonder how it'll go. Can we pull it off from here?
これあれね、なんかさ、強い目もわかんないね。
This thing, you know, I don't even know what the strong symbols are.
ねえ、みんな大好きで！
Hey, everyone loves it!
全然当たんない。ずるん！
It's not hitting at all. Spin!
はい！あ、待って待って、てるてるて、あ！
Here! Ah, wait, wait, teru-teru-te, ah!
はい！あ、みんながいる、みんながいるよ！あ、来た緑！
Here! Ah, everyone's here, everyone's here! Ah, green came!
来た緑！来ただ！熱い熱い！みんな、みんな行くぞ！はっ！
Green came! It came! Hot, hot! Everyone, let's go! Ha!
うわ、来たぞ！これチェリー来たぞ！
Whoa, it's here! Cherries are here!
揃ったよ！これ、ありますね！
They lined up! This is looking good!
緑に発色させなきゃ。つるーん！
I gotta make it glow green. Swoosh!
え、何これ何これ何これ！？
Eh, what is this, what is this, what is this?!
え、とんでもないけど！え？はい！
Whoa, this is insane! Eh? Here!
いや、マジで当たる！絶対当たる！さっきみんなが、
No, seriously, it'll hit! Definitely hit! Everyone earlier—
みんなががたくさんスーパーチャットを送ってくれたから！
everyone sent so many Super Chats!
あの、後ろに立ってるはずなんで！
Um, they should be standing behind me!
バーン！
Bam!
うわあ！やったあ！
Whoa! Yay!
こんなこともあったね、こんなことも見たくだったんでしょ？
Things like this happened too, you wanted to see this kind of thing, right?
つるーん！
Swoosh!
これは…は、もしかしたらこれ当たる次第では、あ、水着揃う？
This is... ha, could it be depending on if this hits, ah, swimsuit match?
あ、揃いそう！揃いそう！バーバーバーバーバー！
Ah, looks like a match! Ba-ba-ba-ba-bam!
はい！
Here!
これは、これは来ますね。
This one, this one is coming.
チャンス目かな？
Is it a chance symbol?
行きますよ！赤に発色したみんな！みんなー！
Here we go! Everyone who turned it red! Everyone!
揃う、当たる気満々じゃん！はい、つるーん！
It's totally going to match! Yes, swoosh!
ああ、なんだ、プリンスかと思ったのに。
Ah, man, I thought it was a Prince.
え？え？え？え？そんな、え？直当たり？
Eh? Eh? Eh? Eh? No way, eh? Direct hit?
もしかして、直ビッグ？
Could it be a direct Big?
え！？え！？これ貴重なの！？貴重なのこれビッグじゃないの！？
Eh?! Eh?! Is this rare?! Is this a Big?!
行くよ！行くよ！せーの！
Here we go! Here we go! Ready, set!
はい！
Bam!
え、何これ、何これ！？え、マジで知らないんだよね、坂本。なにも。
Eh, what is this, what is this?! Eh, seriously, Sakamata doesn't know anything about this. Nothing at all.
どれだけがんばりゃいい
How hard should I work?
誰のためなの？
Is it for someone else?
分かっているのに
Even though I know,
決意は揺らぐ
my resolve wavers.
結末ばかりに気を取られ
So focused on the end result,
この瞬間を楽しめない
I can't enjoy this moment.
メマイ メマイ
Dizzy, dizzy...
夢じゃない あれもこれも
It's no dream, this and that—
その手でドアを開けましょう
let's open the door with our own hands!
祝福が欲しいのなら
If you want a blessing,
悲しみを知り 独りで泣きましょう
then know the sorrow and cry alone.
そして輝く ウルトラソウル
And shine, ultra soul!
ウルトラソウル！
Ultra soul!
はい！
Hey!
おのれの限界に 気づいたつもりかい?
You think you've reached your limits?
かすり傷さえも 無いまま終わりそう
You'll end up with not even a scratch.
一番大事な人がほら いつでもあなたを見ている
The most important person in your life is always watching you.
I can tell
夢じゃない あれもこれも 今こそ胸をはりましょう
It's no dream, this and that, now's the time to be proud!
祝福が欲しいのなら 底無しのペイン 迎えてあげましょう
If you want a blessing, I'll welcome you with bottomless pain!
そして戦う ウルトラソウル
And fight for the ultra soul!
希望と失望に遊ばれて 鍛えぬかれるのさ
Played with hope and disappointment, I'm forged—
Do it Do it Do it
夢じゃない あれもこれは 今こそ胸をはりましょう
It's no dream, this and that, now's the time to be proud!
祝福が欲しいのなら 歓びを知り パーっとばらまき
If you want the blessing, know the joy and scatter it wide!
ホントだらけあれもこれも その真っ只中暴れまくってやりましょう
Let's go wild in the very midst of all that is true!
そして羽ばたく ウルトラソウル
And flap your wings, ultra soul!
ウルトラソウル！
Ultra soul!
一番大事な人がほら いつでもあなたを見ている
The most important person in your life is always watching you.
夢じゃない あれもこれも 今こそ胸をはりましょう
It's no dream, this and that, now's the time to be proud!
祝福が欲しいのなら 底無しのペイン 迎えてあげましょう
If you want a blessing, I'll welcome you with bottomless pain!
そして戦う ウルトラソウル
And fight for the ultra soul!
希望と失望に遊ばれて 鍛えぬかれるのさ
Played with hope and disappointment, I'm forged—
Do it Do it Do it
夢じゃない あれもこれも 今こそ胸をはりましょう
It's no dream, this and that, now's the time to be proud!
祝福が欲しいのなら 歓びを知り パーっとばらまき
If you want the blessing, know the joy and scatter it wide!
ホントだらけあれもこれも その真っ只中暴れまくってやりましょう
Let's go wild in the very midst of all that is true!
そして羽ばたく ウルトラソウル
And flap your wings, ultra soul!
ウルトラソウル！
Ultra soul!
いつもいつものように遊ばれて 期待につかれ
Toyed with as always, tired of expectations—
Do it Do it Do it Do it
夢じゃない あれもこれも 今こそ胸をはりましょう
It's no dream, this and that, now's the time to be proud!
祝福が欲しいのなら 征服が欲しいのなら
If you want a blessing, if you want conquest—
一人占めしてよりましよ
it's better than hoarding it to yourself!
そしてはばたく ウルトラソウル
And flap your wings, ultra soul!
誰かのためなら でもどれも つかったなら
If it's for someone else, but whichever you used—
はげましてよりましよ そしてはばたくウルトラソウル
it's better than cheering, and flap your wings, ultra soul!
そしてハボック ウルトラソウル
And havoc, ultra soul!
はじめてものぼこっとだ
The first thing popped out!
ウルトラソウル！
Ultra soul!
traveling
仕事にも精が出る 金曜の午後
Friday afternoon, working hard too
タクシーもすぐつかまる
I can catch a taxi right away
目指すは君
Heading towards you
「どちらまで行けます?」 ちょっとそこまで
"Where are we going?" "Just nearby"
「ドアに注意」
"Mind the closing door"
風にまたぎ月へ登り
Saddle the wind and climb to the moon
僕の席は君の隣
My seat is right beside you
ふいに我に帰りクラリ
Suddenly coming to my senses, I'm dizzy
春の夜の夢のごとし
Like a dream on a spring night
traveling 君を traveling 乗せて
Traveling, taking you along, traveling
アスファルトを照らすよ
Lighting up the asphalt
traveling どこへ traveling 行くの?
Traveling, where are we heading? Traveling
遠くなら何処へでも
Anywhere as long as it's far away
traveling もっと traveling 揺らせば
Traveling, rocking more, traveling
壊したくなる衝動
The urge to break things
traveling もっと traveling 飛ばせば
Traveling, speeding more, traveling
急ぐことはないけれど
Though there's no need to rush
traveling 胸を traveling 寄せて
Traveling, getting closer, traveling
いつもより目立っちゃおう
Standing out more than usual
travelingここは traveling いやよ
Traveling, not here, traveling
目的地は まだだよ
We still have a way to go
traveling 窓を traveling 下げては
Traveling, rolling down windows, traveling
何も恐くないモード
Fearless mode for anything
traveling ここで traveling いいよ
Traveling, right here is fine, traveling
全ては気分次第
Everything depends on the mood
聞かせたい歌がある
There's a song I want you to hear
エンドレスリピート
An endless repeat
気持ちに拍車がかかる
Emotions running high
狙い通り
Just as planned
波とはしゃぎ雲を誘い
Playing with waves and coaxing clouds
ついに僕は君に出会い
Finally, I meet you
若さ故にすぐにチラリ
Quick to show it off in my youth
風の前の塵に同じ
Like dust before the wind
traveling 胸を traveling 寄せて
Traveling, bringing our chests together, traveling
いつもより目立っちゃおう
Standing out more than ever
traveling ここは traveling いやよ
Traveling, not here, traveling
目的地は まだだよ
We still have a long way to go
traveling 窓を traveling 下げては
Traveling, rolling the window down, traveling
何も恐くないモード
Fearless mode for everything
traveling ここで traveling いいよ
Traveling, right here is good, traveling
全ては気分次第
Everything depends on my mood
みんな踊りだす時間がんだ
Everyone starts to dance
待ちきれず今夜
Can't wait any longer tonight
隠してた願いがうずくんだ
Hidden wishes are throbbing
みんな盛り上がる時間がんだ
Everyone gets excited
どうしてだろうか
How should I put it?
少しだけ不安が残るんだ
A little anxiety remains
どうしてだろうか
Why is that?
少しだけ怖いんだ
Just a little bit scared
traveling 君を traveling 乗せて
Traveling, taking you along, traveling
アスファルトを照らすよ
Lighting up the asphalt
traveling どこに traveling いるの?
Traveling, where are you? Traveling
これからがいいところ
The good part starts from here
traveling もっと traveling 揺らせば
Traveling, rocking more, traveling
壊したくなる衝動
The urge to break things
traveling もっと traveling 飛ばせば
Traveling, speeding more, traveling
止まるのが怖い ちょっと
It's a bit scary to stop
はーいみんな！
Hi everyone!
ちょっとあの坂下にスロットあんのかなって知らなかったんですが、
I didn't know there was a slot machine down the slope,
めちゃくちゃ面白かった！ありがとう！
but it was super fun! Thank you!
みんなのゾロ目も届いてたしね、
Everyone's triple-matching numbers reached me too,
みんなのね、スパチャとかコメントとか、ツイートのツイートとか、
everyone's super chats, comments, and tweets,
そのおかげで当たったのかもしれない、わかんないですけどね。
maybe that's why I won, I don't really know though.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
ウルトラソウル坂下、
Ultra Soul Sakashita—
これやりたくてさ、もはや名次のスタンプ、追加スタンプにあるウルトラソウル！ハイ！ってやりたかった。
I wanted to do this, so I wanted to do the "Ultra Soul! Hey!" from the name stamp.
ちょっとカメラマンさんのこと殴らしていただいたりしましたけれど、ありがとうございます！
I ended up punching the cameraman a bit, but thank you!
トラベリングはですね、ちょっと坂下、
As for Traveling, Sakashita—
今回のグッズにね、あの、関係してるので、ここでグッズ紹介なんてそうしていただけても嬉しい演出かなしちゃおう。
since it relates to this merchandise, let's introduce the goods right here!
しちゃおう。
Let's do it.
はいということで、トラベリングでいっぱい旅をしてきたということで、今回のグッズはこちら！
Alright, having traveled a lot with Traveling, our merchandise this time is right here!
じゃーん、テーマは旅行です。
Ta-da! The theme is travel.
坂下はシークインさんとちょっと一緒にたくさん色々なところに行きたいと思いまして、今回のグッズを考えました。
Sakashita wanted to go to lots of different places together with Sequin-san, and that's how I came up with this merchandise.
警備員らは温泉街フロ上がり坂下です。え、お風呂に入ったんだってね。
Not security, but hot spring town post-bath Sakashita. Oh, you took a bath?
で、天才パパセリが今回もやってくれました、まずは、こちら！
And genius illustrator Paseri-san came through for us again. First up, this!
はいこちらですね、タペストリーになっていますので飾ってほしい。いやマジでこのおっぱいですよねやっぱりね。
Yes, here we have a tapestry, so I want you to display it. I mean seriously, these boobs are amazing, aren't they?
おっぱいが素晴らしかったり、なんか太もももすごいギリギリまで見えちゃったりなんかして、えちちだなと思います。飾ってください。
The boobs are wonderful, and you can see right up to the thighs, so I think it's quite lewd. Please display it.
そして続いては、こちら！
And next is this!
はい万年カレンダー！旅行や坂下の配信ごとに1個めのこの左端のね、キューブを好きなデザインにしたりしてほしいです。
Yes, a perpetual calendar! For every travel or Sakashita stream, customize this cube on the far left.
坂下は机のの上に飾ります。あの、最近は机、あ、きれいなんだよね。うん、まあ、まあまあ、うん、はい。
Sakashita displays hers on her desk. Um, lately my desk, ah, is clean. Yeah, well, sort of, yeah, right.
続いてこちら！
Moving on to this!
トラベルポーチ！普段使いをするなら、まあかばんの中に入れたりとかモバイルバッテリーとか入れてほしいなって。あと女の子とかもね、お化粧品とか小物入れてほしいななんて思います。
A travel pouch! For everyday use, put it in your bag or use it for mobile batteries. And for girls too, put cosmetics in it.
旅行に行くときとかはね、あの、お風呂に行くようなね、小さいポーチみたいな感じで持ってったら、なんか、えんじょいのいこの、って思って頑張って作りましたので、小さい坂下も実はいるよ。
When traveling, if you carry it like a small bath pouch, it'll be enjoyable, so I worked hard to make it. There's actually a tiny Sakashita on it too.
いるよ。え、何？
There is. Eh, what?
は？お風呂、は？お風呂入りじゃないんですけど、は？お風呂入ってますけど！え、今日お風呂入ってきましたよ、さすがに坂下、汗もかきますしね、ねえ？
Huh? Bath, huh? It's not post-bath, but huh? I do take baths! Eh, I took a bath today, of course, Sakashita sweats too, right?
ね、みんな、ね？ね？
Right, everyone? Right? Right?
カメラマンさんすごい今顔伏せてる。え、え、え、くさい？大丈夫？え、大丈夫そんなの聞いたんだけど、大丈夫？
The cameraman is covering his face right now. Eh, eh, eh, does it smell? Are you okay asking something like that?
あの、入ってきましたよね？あー、すごいゆっくりこう、なんか、はい、みたいな。
Um, I came in, right? Ah, very slowly like, yeah, something like that.
頷いていただきました、ありがとうございます！はい、坂下はね、旅行中しっかりと、お風呂に入る人ですから！
You nodded, thank you! Yes, Sakashita is someone who properly takes a bath while traveling!
そして、こちら！
And, this!
坂下ぬいぐるみ！これめちゃくちゃいいよ！
Sakashita plushie! This is insanely good!
こちらめちゃくちゃ細部にこだわりました、かわいいですよ、これ！超かわいい、これ本当に！フード着脱から始まってね、細かい装飾を頑張って再現しましたので、旅行に行くときに一緒に坂下を連れてってほしいです。
We paid extreme attention to detail, it's so cute! From the detachable hood to the fine decorations, I worked hard to recreate it, so take Sakashita along when you travel.
商品到着後にぬいぐるみを使ってフォトコンテスト企画も考えてますので、よろしくお願いします！坂下はベッドの横に飾って、たまに抱きしめたりして使おうと思ってるので2個買います。
Since we're planning a photo contest using the plushie after arrival, please look forward to it! I'm going to display Sakashita next to my bed and hug her sometimes, so I'm buying two.
あと、シチュエーションボイスがね、あるんですよ。
Also, there's a situation voice pack.
こちらは、え、温泉街でシークインさんとデートをしている感じなので、まあ一緒にデートをしようみたいな感じです。全部セット特典は、
This is like going on a date with Sequin-san in a hot spring town, so it's like going on a date together. The all-in-one set bonus is—
直筆メッセージポストカードと特典ボイスが付きます！
A handwritten message postcard and bonus voice!
今回もね、ポストカードは坂下メッセージを直筆で書かせていただきたいと思います。
This time too, I'd like to write Sakashita's message by hand on the postcard.
なんかね、まあ、たぶんなんだけど、3種類ぐらい書こうかなと思っているので、ちゃんと読んでください。
I think I'm going to write about 3 different types, so make sure to read them.
はい、坂下はちゃんと書くので、皆さん読んでください。解読班はいません、読んでください。
Yes, Sakashita will write them properly, so everyone please read them. There are no decoders needed, just read them.
はい、特典ボイスはのぼせタ坂下なので、解放してもらえたらなと、思います。あの、本当に温泉ね、苦手なんです。はい。はい。
Yes, the bonus voice is fainting-from-heat Sakashita, so I hope you'll unlock it. Um, I really am bad at hot springs. Yes. Yes.
そして、次でね、最後の曲になるんですが
And next will be the final song, but...
今日で沙花叉がデビューして1年が経つということで、
today marks one year since Sakamata debuted,
あの初配信からもう1年なんですが、
it's been a year since that first stream,
まあ、みんなにはね、1年間沙花叉を見てもらったりとかしたと思うので、
so I think you've all watched Sakamata for a whole year,
ちょっといろんな応援してきてくれたシークレットたちに感謝の気持ちなど返ってきたんだの、見てほしいのかなって思いますけど、はい。
and I wanted to return my gratitude to all the Secret agents who supported me in various ways... I hope you'll watch it.
じゃあ、行くよ。
Well then, here we go.
みんな、今日は沙花叉の1周年ライブに来てくれてありがとう。
Everyone, thank you for coming to Sakamata's 1st anniversary live today.
そして順調とは言えない1年でみんなにたくさん心配かけちゃってごめんね。
And I'm sorry for causing you so much worry during a year that hasn't exactly been smooth sailing.
今こうして元気に毎日楽しく活動できているのは応援してくれるみんなの言葉があったからです。
The reason I can cheerfully and happily stream every day like this now is because of the words of everyone who cheered me on.
本当だよね。いつも沙花叉を支えてくれてありがとう。
That's right. Thank you always for supporting Sakamata.
まあ、ちょっと、なんか…
Well, um, somehow...
まだまだ沙花叉の活動は始まったばかり。地道に頑張ってみんなとの日々を愉しんでいくので、これからの沙花叉を見てください。
Sakamata's activities have only just begun. I'll steadily work hard and enjoy everyday life with everyone, so please keep watching Sakamata from now on.
やばいやばいやばい
Oh no, oh no, oh no!
そしてよければ沙花叉のそばにいてください。
And if you'd like, please stay by Sakamata's side.
いつもありがとう。大好きだよ。
Thank you as always. I love you.
はい、ありがとうございます。
Yes, thank you.
危ない危ない危ない。ちょっと危ない危ない。
Careful, careful, careful. That was close, close.
はい、お？もこ？もこもこ？え？
Yes, oh? Moko? Moko moko? Eh?
あれ？このもこもこはもしや？
Huh? Could this fluffy thing be...?
お、お、お、お、お？お、これって？
Oh, oh, oh, oh? Oh, what is this?
もしかして？ って、もしかして？
Could it be? Could it really be?
わ、どんどんもこもこしてきてんじゃない？
Wow, isn't it getting fluffier and fluffier?
どんどんもこもこしてきてる！うわ、わ、わ、すごいすごいすごい！
It's getting fluffier and fluffier! Wow, wow, wow, amazing, amazing!
すごい、なんだこれ！うわああ！うわあ、なんか微妙に透けてる。にゃ、にゃ、みんな、みんな見て、見てね！
Amazing, what is this?! Whoa! Whoa, it looks slightly transparent. Meow, meow, everyone, everyone look, look!
よかった。
Oh, thank goodness.
では、聞いてください、「Story」。
Now, please listen to "Story."
限られた時間の中で
In the limited time we have,
どれだけのコトが出来るのだろう…
how much can we actually do...
言葉にならないほどの想いを
Feelings that are hard to put into words,
どれだけアナタに伝えられるだろう…
how much of them can I convey to you...
ずっと閉じ込めてた
The pain in my heart that I had kept locked away
胸の痛みを消してくれた
for so long, you wiped away.
今私が笑えるのは
The reason I can smile now
一緒に泣いてくれたキミがいたから
is because you were there, crying with me.
一人じゃないから キミが私を守るから
Because I'm not alone, because you protect me,
強くなれる もう何も怖くないよ…
I can become strong, I'm no longer afraid of anything...
時がなだめてく 痛みと共に流れてく
Time gently soothes, flowing away along with the pain,
日の光がやさしく照らしてくれる
and the sunlight gently shines down upon us.
説明する言葉も
Explanatory words,
ムリして笑うコトもしなくていいから
or forcing yourself to smile, you don't need to do either,
何かあるなら いつでも頼ってほしい
so if anything's wrong, I want you to rely on me anytime.
疲れた時は 肩をかすから
When you're tired, I'll lend you my shoulder,
どんなに強がっても
no matter how strong you try to act,
ため息くらいする時もある
there are times when you'll sigh.
孤独じゃ重い扉も
Even heavy doors of solitude...
共に立ち上がれればまた動き始める
if we stand together, they'll start moving again.
一人じゃないから 私がキミを守るから
Because you're not alone, I will protect you.
あなたの笑う顔が見たいと思うから
Because I want to see your smiling face.
時がなだめてく 痛みと共に流れてく
Time will soothe it, flowing away with the pain.
日の光がやさしく照らしてくれる
Sunlight will gently shine down on you.
時に人は傷付き、傷付けながら
Sometimes people get hurt and hurt others,
染まる色はそれぞれ違うケド
though the colors we dye ourselves are different.
自分だけの Story 作りながら生きてくのだからずっと
We live on, weaving our own unique story, so always...
あきらめないで
never give up.
一人じゃないから 私がキミを守るから
Because you're not alone, I will protect you.
あなたの笑う顔が見たいと思うから
Because I want to see your smiling face.
時がなだめてく 痛みと共に流れてく
Time will soothe it, flowing away with the pain.
日の光がやさしく照らしてくれる
Sunlight will gently shine down on you.